[
  {
      "question": "The files stored on a secondary stage device are composed of a hierarchy of data. What does a record in a file contain?",
      "options": [
          "Characters",
          "Data field",
          "Bits",
          "Schema"
      ],
      "answer": "Data field"
  },
  {
      "question": "A report generator is used to____________",
      "options": [
          "print files on paper",
          "update files",
          "data entry",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "print files on paper"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which command is used to remove an index from the database in SQL?",
      "options": [
          "REMOVE INDEX",
          "DROP INDEX",
          "DELETE INDEX",
          "ROLL BACK INDEX"
      ],
      "answer": "DROP INDEX"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the name given to the database management system which is able to handle full text data, image data, audio and video?",
      "options": [
          "Graphics media",
          "Multimedia",
          "Full media",
          "Hypertext"
      ],
      "answer": "Multimedia"
  },
  {
      "question": "The relational model uses some unfamiliar terminology. A tuple is equivalent to a____________-",
      "options": [
          "file",
          "field",
          "record",
          "data base"
      ],
      "answer": "record"
  },
  {
      "question": "An-owner-member set in the CODASYL specifications may have__________",
      "options": [
          "only one member but many member occurrence",
          "only one owner but many owner occurrences",
          "more than one member but only one occurrence per member",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "only one owner but many owner occurrences"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a logical data-base structure?",
      "options": [
          "relational",
          "network",
          "tree",
          "chain"
      ],
      "answer": "chain"
  },
  {
      "question": "If the record management system allows you to edit values before they are recorded on disk, you can________",
      "options": [
          "change the name of a field",
          "correct spelling changes before they are recorded",
          "change the width of a field",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "correct spelling changes before they are recorded"
  },
  {
      "question": "A top-to-bottom relationship among the items in a database is established by a__________",
      "options": [
          "Network schema",
          "Relational schema",
          "Hierarchical schema",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Hierarchical schema"
  },
  {
      "question": "A database management system___________",
      "options": [
          "is a collection of programs for managing data in a single file",
          "can do more than a record management system",
          "allows simultaneous access to multiple files",
          "Both 2 & 3"
      ],
      "answer": "Both 2 & 3"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which of the following is a database administrator’s function?",
      "options": [
          "performance monitoring",
          "backing up the database",
          "database design",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
      "question": "In SQL, which command(s) is(are) used to enable/disable a database trigger?",
      "options": [
          "CHANGE USER",
          "ALTER TRIGGER",
          "MODIFY USER",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "ALTER TRIGGER"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which of the following hardware components is the most important to the operation of a database management system?",
      "options": [
          "high speed, large-capacity disk",
          "printer",
          "high-resolution video display",
          "plotter"
      ],
      "answer": "high speed, large-capacity disk"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which of the following is not a relational database?",
      "options": [
          "4th Dimension",
          "FoxPro",
          "dBASE IV",
          "Reflex"
      ],
      "answer": "Reflex"
  },
  {
      "question": "The data dictionary tells the DBMS_________",
      "options": [
          "what these files contain",
          "what attribute are possessed by the data",
          "what files are in the database",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
      "question": "The PROJECT command will create new table that has___________",
      "options": [
          "more rows than the original table",
          "all the fields of master table",
          "more fields than the original table",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "None of the above"
  },
  {
      "question": "Primitive operations common to all record management systems include____________",
      "options": [
          "Print",
          "Look-up",
          "Sort",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "Look-up"
  },
  {
      "question": "Which two files are used during operation of the DBMS?",
      "options": [
          "data manipulation language and query language",
          "data dictionary and transaction log",
          "query language and utilities",
          "data dictionary and query language"
      ],
      "answer": "data dictionary and transaction log"
  },
  {
      "question": "In a _____ a parent record type can be linked to one or more “child” record types, but a child record type can have only one parent.",
      "options": [
          "Distributed database",
          "Relational database",
          "Network database",
          "Hierarchical database"
      ],
      "answer": "Hierarchical database"
  },
  {
      "question": "Sort/report generators_________",
      "options": [
          "require more disk space than index/report generators",
          "do not need to sort before generating a report",
          "are faster than index/report generators",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "require more disk space than index/report generators"
  },
  {
      "question": "Each of data files has a _____ that describe the way the data is stored in the file.",
      "options": [
          "Records",
          "File structure",
          "Fields",
          "Database"
      ],
      "answer": "File structure"
  },
  {
      "question": "To have a file hold a list, it is necessary to________",
      "options": [
          "identify the records in the list",
          "decide which fields will be used as sort or index keys",
          "identify the name, width and type of the fields of each record",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
      "question": "Periodically adding, changing and deleting file records is called file__________",
      "options": [
          "upgrading",
          "Updating",
          "renewing",
          "restructuring"
      ],
      "answer": "Updating"
  },
  {
      "question": "After you _____ a record, many data management the environments require you to issue a command to save the changes you made.",
      "options": [
          "Update",
          "Delete",
          "Sort key",
          "Index"
      ],
      "answer": "Update"
  },
  {
      "question": "Sophisticated report generators can________",
      "options": [
          "perform arithmetic operations",
          "print row-oriented reports",
          "selectively retrieve and print portions of a list",
          "All of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "All of the above"
  },
  {
      "question": "In SQL, which command is used to make permanent changes made by statements issue since the beginning of a transaction?",
      "options": [
          "COMMIT",
          "PACK",
          "SAVE",
          "ZIP"
      ],
      "answer": "COMMIT"
  },
  {
      "question": "What is the language used by most of the DBMSs for helping their users to access data?",
      "options": [
          "4GL",
          "Query language",
          "High level language",
          "SQL"
      ],
      "answer": "Query language"
  },
  {
      "question": "A network schema__________",
      "options": [
          "stores data in tables",
          "permits many-to-many relation¬ships",
          "restricts the structure to a one-to-many relationship",
          "None of the above"
      ],
      "answer": "permits many-to-many relation¬ships"
  },
  {
      "question": "When using a database management system, the first thing that you must do is to____________",
      "options": [
          "activate file editor",
          "create a database file",
          "load the Software into your microcomputer",
          "keep a floppy disk in readiness"
      ],
      "answer": "load the software into your micro¬computer"
  },
  {
      "question": "Data item characteristics that are important in data management include____________",
      "options": [
          "language",
          "spelling",
          "punctuation",
          "Width"
      ],
      "answer": "Width"
  }
]
